

# Pranjal Dewangan

Upcoming IIIT graduate offering a strong foundation in software engineering and programming principles across multiple platforms. Experienced in object-oriented programming and development. Quickly learn and master new technologies; successful working in both team and self-directed settings.

pranjal16100@alumni.iiitnr.ac.in

Raipur, India

in linkedin.com/in/pranjal-dewangan

8839470226

pranjal-dew.github.io

github.com/Pranjal-dew

### **EDUCATION**

### **B.Tech Computer Science**

International Institute of Information Technology, Naya Raipur, India

08/2016 - 11 / 2019

6.7 CGPA

### **PROJECTS**

Fraudulent Detection of Anonymized Sensitive Transactional Data (07/2019 - 11 / 2019)

Fraud detection is a complex issue and requires a major modification.
 We are trying to provide better accuracy by combining adaptive mining and neural network approach.

Handwritten character generation for Indian Languages using GAN (01/2019 - 06/2019)

 Trained a deep learning model which can mimic one's handwritten style for Indian languages like Hindi and Telugu using GANs.

Parkinson's and Alzheimer's proteins Relation Mining in literature (07/2018 - 12/2018)

 Collecting all the proteins related to Alzheimer's and Parkinson disease based on their protein id's (provided by research lab) which is being mined on the PubMed website, thereby generating a network.

E-commerce website : naivedyasweets.com (08/2018 - 10/2018)

A live project, minimalistic design with gathered requirements.

Hand Gestures Robotic Arm using Raspberry Pi via Android App (01/2018 - 06/2018)

 As the title suggests this prototype's working while it's purpose is to help disabled person.

### **EXPERIENCE**

### **Web Development**

Entrepreneurship Cell, IIIT NR

06/2018 - 06/2019 India

International Institute of Information Technology, Naya Raipur E-CELL.

 Developed & monitored a website to make aware and influence people about the ongoing entrepreneur events.

## Design & Promotion Head

Technovate 2018 & 2019, IIIT NR

10/2017 - 06/2019 India International Institute of Information Technology, Nava Raipur Techfest.

 Mentored and trained students for promoting the genuine content for targeted customer using Digital Marketing.

### SKILL

C / C++ Data structures & Algorithms JAVA

Django Framework Problem Solving Python

LINUX Git

### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

Winner of Application Development Competition (2017)

Contest held in Technovate 2017 (College Fest). Contribution: User Interface designing and backend development using firebase.

Among the top 10 students who qualified for JEE Main Architecture (2015)

For B. Planning aspirants, this exam include aptitude and mathematics subsections where Aptitude is a key factor.

### CERTIFICATES

Java Certificate (2020)

Hackerrank

Seminar on Symposium on Data Science and Business Analytics (2017)

By Prof. Dr. ArtusKrohn-Grimberghe, University of Paderborn, Germany

### **KNOWN LANGUAGES**

English Hindi

Professional Working Proficiency Full Professional Proficiency

#### INTERESTS

Puzzle Solving Development Club Memberships

Problem Solving Graphic Designing